# Masoud Asadzadeh

# C# .NET Backend Developer

Switzerland, Lugano (Swiss B Permit with work permit, open for relocation) masoud.asadzade@gmail.com

**\** +41779666625 in LinkedIn

Language: English GitHub



## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Hamfekran Information Technology Group (2013–2020)

Backend Developer (2020 (remote))

## Project: Government Service, User Monitoring, and Ticketing

- Contributed to the development of REST APIs on Service Oriented architecture with the focus on connecting the internal government system to on-line interfaces and allowing citizens to transact with government entities to renew their licenses, to pay tax/fines/car tolls/property tolls
- Created backend for single page event log analyzer & ticketing application.

# Backend Developer (2018-2019 (remote)) Project: AutoTaxi (ETAXI)

- Designed and developed workflows and processes for taxi-business to serve taxi companies' needs of metropolitan cities such as buying/selling taxies, issuing driving certificates, school services.
- Participated in the design and development of service oriented architecture to meet the process-oriented business needs.
- Achieved improvement in the system's speed by 50% and enhanced scalability and maintainability.

# Backend Developer (2016–2017)

# **Project: E-Commerce Application (Epardis)**

- Designed and developed backend and database for NopCommerce (open source E-commerce) for booking services such as catering, equipment hire, and car rental.
- Unified the process of document generation and transmission engine by building a set of libraries and interfaces (E-Letters).

## Backend Developer (2014-2017)

#### **Project: Automation of Vehicle Technical Inspection (VTI)**

- Automated the recognition and image processing of vehicles' number
- Assisted to record inspection hardware outputs & to issue the certification.
- Established a fully customizable inspection software for users across the country.

# FullStack Developer (2013-2016)

## **Project: Funeral Service Management**

- When I was hired, the FSM Application was scattered into decentralized apps which had massive cost on support, development, and maintenance.
- Achieved, roughly, a 200% improvement in performance by developing a centralized webApp Automating Burial and Funeral Procedure, supporting selling gravesites, custom reports as well as integrating with BI programs.

# Independent Contract (2013-2014)

#### End to End Developer

# **Project: Supply Chain Automation - Textile, Home Furnishing**

- Developed core functionalities of SCM operations for the management of customer orders, sourcing, logistics, warehouse, and payroll, financial operations, inventory, distribution, etc.
- Exported invoices to MS excel and Crystal reporting service to save time and money by removing paper works.

#### **ABOUT**

A software developer with a demonstrated history in the industry who worked on commercial countrywide and corporate ITtype applications, developing and maintaining newly developed and legacy progressive apps utilizing ORD and .NET in a scrum team. Willing to learn who can play a reliable and loyal role in a team.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages	Years
C#	••••
C++	••••
TSQL	••••
HTML, JavaScript, CSS	••••
Web Frameworks	
ASP.NET Web Forms	••••
ASP.NET MVC	••••
.NET Core	••••
<b>Desktop Frameworks</b>	
Windows Forms	••••
WPF	••••
<b>Communication Frameworks</b>	
ASP.NET WebAPI/RESTful	••••
WCF	
ASMX web Service/SOAP	••••
ORM	
ORIVI	
Entity Framework	••••
	••••
Entity Framework	
Entity Framework ADO.NET, LINQ	
Entity Framework ADO.NET, LINQ  DataBases MS SQL Server	••••
Entity Framework ADO.NET, LINQ  DataBases MS SQL Server  Reporting	••••
Entity Framework ADO.NET, LINQ  DataBases MS SQL Server  Reporting MS SQL Reporting Service	••••
Entity Framework ADO.NET, LINQ  DataBases MS SQL Server  Reporting MS SQL Reporting Service Crystal Reports	••••
Entity Framework ADO.NET, LINQ  DataBases MS SQL Server  Reporting MS SQL Reporting Service Crystal Reports  Versioning and Build Tools	••••
Entity Framework ADO.NET, LINQ  DataBases MS SQL Server  Reporting MS SQL Reporting Service Crystal Reports  Versioning and Build Tools TFS, MicrosoftVisualStudio	••••
Entity Framework ADO.NET, LINQ  DataBases MS SQL Server  Reporting MS SQL Reporting Service Crystal Reports  Versioning and Build Tools TFS, MicrosoftVisualStudio  3rd Party .NET	••••
Entity Framework ADO.NET, LINQ  DataBases MS SQL Server  Reporting MS SQL Reporting Service Crystal Reports  Versioning and Build Tools TFS, MicrosoftVisualStudio  3rd Party .NET DNN (CMS)	••••
Entity Framework ADO.NET, LINQ  DataBases MS SQL Server  Reporting MS SQL Reporting Service Crystal Reports  Versioning and Build Tools TFS, MicrosoftVisualStudio  3rd Party .NET	•••••
Entity Framework ADO.NET, LINQ  DataBases MS SQL Server  Reporting MS SQL Reporting Service Crystal Reports  Versioning and Build Tools TFS, MicrosoftVisualStudio  3rd Party .NET DNN (CMS)	

**SDLC** 

Agile development/Scrum

Solid principle, DesignPattern

#### FREELANCING PROJECTS

#### Legacy Migration on Real Estate Portfolio Management

Contributed to the migration of MS Access database to SQL Server and Web Form app into MVC.

#### **Automation System of Transportation**

Developed a distributed desktop solution that offers transportation services throughout the country. All orders are logged from the registration time to delivery time using RFID tech.

# Flight Information Display App

Created an application to display real-time flight information for passengers can be used in airports and hotels. It can be connected to online flight information data source and customizable to show Ads.

#### WCF Service front-ended by USSD

Developed a service to issue up to 15-thousands real-time permits a day to control the entrance of vehicles into traffic zones.

#### **Payment Provider**

Worked with POS terminals SDK for developing payment providers.

#### **Facial Navigator Speaker**

Implemented a voice-face recognition prototype for navigation purpose using EmguCV (.NET wrapper for C++ OpenCV computer vision library). Composed of six components: Face Detector, face database, Training Set Manager, Face Recognizer, speaker, Speech Recognizer.

## **EDUCATION**

B.Sc in Software Engineering University of Science and Culture (2005–2010) 
♥ Tehran, Iran

## **TEACHING ASSISTANT**

Internet engineering, Advanced Programming

## **PUBLICATION**

Forecasting rail transport petroleum consumption using an integrated model of autocorrelation functions-artificial neural network. Journal of Acta Polytechnica Hungarica, 11(2), 203-214.

## **SOFT SKILS**

Cooperative, adaptable, enthusiastic about learning, and reliable.

#### **HOBBIES**

Watching Documentaries

Reading A Hiking